An intimate bioscopic experience with The Beatles.
Let It Be is a documentary, music film directed by Michael Lindsay-Hogg.
A documentary chronicling the Beatles' rehearsal sessions in January 1969 for their proposed
"back to basics" album, "Get Back," later re-envisioned and released as "Let It Be."
Self - The Beatles (uncredited), played by John Lennon.
Self - The Beatles (uncredited), played by Paul McCartney.
Self - The Beatles (uncredited), played by George Harrison.
Self - The Beatles (uncredited), played by Ringo Starr.
Self (uncredited), played by Billy Preston.
Self (uncredited), played by George Martin.
Let It Be is a 1970 British documentary film starring the
Beatles and directed by Michael Lindsay-Hogg.
The film documents the group's rehearsing and recording songs in January 1969 for
what was to become their twelfth and final studio album Let It Be.
The film ends with an unannounced rooftop concert by the
group, their last public performance together.
The film was originally planned as a television documentary
that would accompany a concert broadcast.
When plans for the concert were dropped, the project
became a feature film production.
Although Let It Be does not dwell on the dissension within the Beatles at the time, it
provides some glimpses into the dynamics that would lead to their break-up.
After the film's release, John Lennon, Paul McCartney, George Harrison and
Ringo Starr won an Academy Award for Best Original Song Score.
Footage filmed for Let It Be was later restored and re-edited for
Peter Jackson's 2021 documentary The Beatles: Get Back.
Let It Be had not been officially available on home video since the
1980s, although bootleg copies of the film still circulated.
While attempts to release the film on DVD and Blu-ray have not come to fruition, a restored 4K version
of the film was made available to stream on Disney+ for the first time on 8 May 2024.
The film explores themes of concert, studio, rock band.